urlspy.co.uk 2019-07-18

# Privacy Policy

We have created a Privacy Policy that aims to help you understand what data we collect, what we use it for and how you can exercise your rights. The privacy of our users is of extreme importance to us. 

##  1\. What we collect 

Like many other Web sites, we make use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, and track user's movement around the site. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

**When you contact us**  
While you can use our website without giving out your personal information, once you contact us via the website, or by email, we collect information about you. The information you fill in (personal information such as your name, email address, organisation) may be processed and stored so that it is possible for us to contact and respond to your request, and/or allow you access to our services. 

##  2\. How we use cookies 

"Cookies" are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. 

We use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser. 

### Advertising

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include; Google Adsense, Skimlinks. 

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on this website sent directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see. 

We have no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Our privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. 

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**

(i) Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this website.   
(ii) Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to this website and other sites on the Internet.   
(iii) Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

**SkimLinks**

We make use of Skimlinks on some pages to help monetize existing links out to other merchant websites. This means we might receive a commission for sales originated from users referred from our website. EU based users will be alerted to these links when clicked, and will have the option to refuse tracking. 

Users also have the option to opt out of skimlinks cookies at the following link:   
<https://optout.skimlinks.com/?tested=1>

You can review Skimlinks privacy & cookie policies here:   
<https://skimlinks.com/privacy-policy>   
<https://skimlinks.com/user-cookies>

### Analytics

**Google Analytics**  
We use Google Analytics and Cookies to improve our service, user experience and analyse how the website is used. The collected information is used to provide an overview of how people are accessing and using the website. It is not used for any additional purpose, such as to profile specific users. 

Further information and the applicable data protection provisions may be retrieved at:   
<https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>   
<https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>   

Users that don't want their visit data reported by Google Analytics can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

**Statcounter**

We also use StatCounter which uses cookies and other methods to generate statistical information on how visitors use our website. StatCounter will store this information, but is not used to identify individuals. 

Further information is available here:   
<https://statcounter.com/about/legal/#privacy>   
<https://statcounter.com/about/cookies/>   

You have the option to refuse all Statcounter cookies at the following link:   
<https://statcounter.com/about/set-refusal-cookie/>

**Disable cookies**

Aside from the options listed above, if you wish to disable cookies, you may also do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management for specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites, or at http://www.allaboutcookies.org. 

## 3\. Data we publish

We collect & publish accessible data from the open Internet, this includes; 

a. Information about websites using specific web technologies, or hosting providers (non-personal data)   
b. Snippets of website content, like Web page titles, keywords, links etc.   
c. General non-personal information about websites.   

The processing of data for the purpose above will be carried out via automated electronic means only. 

## 4\. Right to erasure

If there is content on our website (urlm.co.uk) that you believe infringes on your rights, you can make a request for deletion: 

I want to remove a website statistics page  
I want to remove my personal information  
I want to remove a trademark, or other issue  

## 5\. Privacy policy changes

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons. 

By using our website you are agreeing to the use of cookies as described, and to abide by our Terms of Service. 

When we refer to ‘we’ (or ‘our’ or ‘us’), that means . We are a New Zealand based company. If you have any concerns or questions regarding use of your personal data, you can contact us here.
